ellie.tt.chen@gmail.com · 0475-255-677

Ellie Chen

Sydney, New South Wales, Australia

<u>linkedin.com/in/elliettchen/</u> · github.com/EllieChen-Git

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Before switching my career to IT, I have had 3 years professional experience in the accounting migration industry. My passion for technology and desire to learn motivated me to pursue a career in web development. During my time with Coder Academy, I was able to plan, design and implement multiple applications from scratch to final products in different stacks (Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and MERN stack). At my internship, I gained valuable commercial production experience using the latest Angular technology. As a developer, I look forward to combining my multi-disciplined domain knowledge and strong programming skills to support both businesses and clients to achieve their desired outcomes.

PROJECTS

Pricing Portal

Deployed site: https://pricing-portal-prod-ern.s3-website-ap-southeast-2.amazonaws.com/
Frontend repo (React App): https://github.com/EllieChen-Git/frontend-pricing-portal-ERN
Backend repo (Express API): https://github.com/INRokh/backend-pricing-portal-ERN

- Image annotation tool to help property professionals to more effectively evaluate property prices.
- MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) application, image annotation, annotation review, role-based authentication, tag and image metadata management.

Aussie Beauty Market

https://aussie-beauty-market.herokuapp.com/

https://github.com/EllieChen-Git/Aussie-Beauty-Market

- Two-sided marketplace website on **Ruby on Rails** for trading second-hand makeup in Australia.
- E-commerce application, **REST API**, **user authentication & authorisation**, simple & advanced search capabilities, payment processing function, Q&A section and responsive web design.

Portfolio Website

https://elliechen.netlify.com/

https://github.com/EllieChen-Git/Portfolio-Site Ellie-Chen

- Portfolio website to showcase my web development skills and to demonstrate my professional experiences, transferable skills, personal projects, interests and personality.
- Different CSS/JavaScript effects on every webpage, fixed navigation bar and social icons bar, accessibility, sub-resource integrity and responsive web design.

COMPETENCIES

- **Programming stacks:** HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), TypeScript, Angular, GraphQL, REST API, Bootstrap and Material UI.
- **Dependencies**: Git, GitHub, AWS (S3, IAM), deployment platforms (Heroku, Netlify), database (Postgres SQL, MongoDB, Hasura), payment processing service (Stripe), wireframe (Balsamiq).

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Intern

Feb 2020 - Mar 2020

Skychute (Sydney, Australia)

- Developing property-related products to enhance people's everyday experience with real estate.
- Implementing full-stack components using TypeScript, Angular, Material UI, GraphQL and Hasura.
- Participating in Agile sprint planning, weekly demo sessions and tech meetups.

Migration Coordinator/Migration Executive

Aug 2016 - Aug 2019

Chartered Accountants Australia & New Zealand (Sydney, Australia)

- Conducting migration assessment with high attention to details and producing training materials.
- Interpreting the latest legislation changes and advising on difficult migration assessment issues.
- Proven time-management skills in handling high volumes of applications, prioritising tasks and working autonomously and cooperatively in a high-performing professional team.

Assistant Migration Consultant

Sep 2014 – Jul 2016

Ausky Visa Solutions (Sydney, Australia)

- Efficiently managing a client's visa application from the initial engagement, eligibility assessment, follow-up correspondence, application lodgment to final decision, with a 95% visa approval rate.
- Effectively facilitating the communication between the mandarin-speaking clients and other
 English-speaking parties, including Immigration case officers and skills assessing authorities.

Localisation Project Manager and Translator

Jul 2010 - Jun 2011

Weasto Translation Company (Taipei, Taiwan)

- Intelligently organising translation projects, conducting human resource deployment of inhouse/freelance translators and editors, and liaising with international clients and local vendors.
- Effectively managing a one-million-words Expedia.com project and achieving scheduled goals.

EDUCATION

Diploma in Information Technology/Full-time Fast-track Bootcamp

Coder Academy (Sydney, Australia)

Aug 2019 - Feb 2020

Graduate Certificate in Australian Migration Law and Practice (High Distinction Average)

The Australian National University (Canberra, Australia)

May 2017 – Nov 2017

Graduate Diploma in Professional Accounting (High Distinction Average)

Victoria University (Sydney, Australia)

Jul 2015 – Apr 2016

Postgraduate Diploma of Translating and Interpreting (Distinction Average)

Macquarie University (Sydney, Australia)

Aug 2014 – Jul 2015

VOLUNTEER

Mentor (Intro to JavaScript Workshop)

Muses Code JS (Sydney, Australia)

Mar 2020 – Current

Mandarin Community Interpreter

Macquarie University (Sydney, Australia)

Apr 2015 – Jul 2015